Limited Editions Club Collection
Limited Editions Club Collection
1929-1968
Limited Editions Club.
.75 linear ft.
Checklists, catalogs, prospectuses from the American publishing company.
2570339
Biographical History
The Limited Editions Club was founded in 1929 by George Macy (1900-1956). It published fine books, usually classics and illustrated by leading artists of the day, for its member/subscribers; membership was limited to 1500. After Macy's death, leadership of the company passed to Macy's wife (1956) and then to his son (1968). In 1970 the Limited Editions Club was purchased by the Boise-Cascade Company and then in 1979 by Sidney Shiff, a Wall Street investor. Shiff focused on enhancing the quality of book design, solicited work from a number of African-American artists, and expanded the firm's offerings to include signed artists' portfolios.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Limited Editions Club Collection consists of annual prospectuses, monthly letters and special items. Annual prospectuses are the descriptive catalogs distributed each year to members, describing that year's books. Monthly Letter contains more than 200 issues of the monthly newsletter sent to subscribers. Special items include the initial prospectus and description of the club (1929), a sample book from the sixth series (1934), a special wartime prospectus for the general public (1942), and the address by Sir Francis Meynell at the dedication of the George Macy Memorial Collection of books (1957).
Arrangement of the Collection
Items in both series are arranged in chronological order.
Subject and Genre Headings
Publishing, printing and book arts; Literature -- American Fiction; Limited Editions Club.; Bibliography -- Catalogs.; Bibliography -- Limited editions.; Privately printed books.; Publishers and publishing.; The address by Sir Francis Meynell at the dedication of the George Macy Memorial Collection of books published by the Limited Editions Club, with a list of the titles, 14 May 1957.; The monthly letter of the Limited Editions Club.; Samples: a book containing fine illustrations and fine pages from the books to be published by the Limited Editions Club in its sixth series.; Ten years and William Shakespeare: a survey of the publishing activities of the Limited editions club from October 1929 to October 1940; Prospectuses.; Catalogs (documents); Checklists.; Sample books.; Publishers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Transfer from Rare Books.
Inventory
- Annual prospectuses
  - Annual prospectuses, 1933-1939 (Box 1)
  - Annual prospectuses, 1940-1944 (Box 1)
  - Annual prospectuses, 1953 (Box 1)
  - Annual prospectuses, 1960-1968 (Box 1)
- Newsletter, issues of the Monthly Letter
  - No's 1-51, Jun 1929 - Dec 1933 (Box 1)
  - No's 52-103, Jan 1934 - Dec 1937 (Box 1)
  - No's 104-117, Jan 1938 - Feb 1939 (Box 1)
  - No's 186, 216, 229, Dec 1947; Jul 1950,; Apr 1952 (Box 1)
  - No's 323-369, Oct 1960 - Oct 1964; some missing issues (Box 1)
- Special items
  - First prospectus, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Sample book for sixth series, 1934 (Box 2)
  - Ten years and William Shakespeare: a survey of the publishing activities of the Limited editions club from October 1929 to October 1940 (Box 2)
  - The address by Sir Francis Meynell at the dedication of the George Macy Memorial Collection of books published by the Limited Editions Club, with a list of the titles, 14 May 1957 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2)